Meyer, Arthur S. Additional Files and Scrapbooks 6045
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Arthur S. Meyer Additional Files and Scrapbooks
1935-1983
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Meyer, Arthur S.
6045
2.33 cubic feet
2.3 linear ft.
Papers, scrapbooks.
5771349
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 26, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 18, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Arthur S. Meyer was a member of the New York State Board of Mediation from its inception in 1937. In 1940, he was appointed as its chairman, a position in which he served until his retirement in 1950. Before becoming a mediator, Meyer was a successful businessman, rising to the posts of president and director of the Schulte Real Estate Company and vice-president of the Schulte Retail Stores Corporation. In 1942, Meyer was named chairman of a U.S. War Labor Board panel to rule on the demands of the Steel Workers Organizing Committee for a raise of one dollar per day and union security. The recommendation of Meyer and his committee formed the basis for a subsequent Board ruling known as the "Little Steel Formula".
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Meyer, Arthur S. (Arthur Simon), 1880-1955
5771349
- Scrap Book, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Strikes 1941 NYC, Jamaica (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Scrap Book 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Arthur S. Meyer Clippings, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Scrap Book, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- November 1946- August 1951, 1946-1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 1937-1939 Scrap Book (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Mrs. Arthur S. Meyer, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Union Readings, 1935-1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 1937-1939 Scrap Book (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Arthur S. Meyer 1945 Annual Wage (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Arthur S. Meyer, 1946-1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Misc. Letters, Newsletters, 1944-1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Misc., 1940-1944 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Arthur S. Meyer Clippings October 1945 - April 1946, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 1942 Scrap Book (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Arthur S. Meyer Clippings August 1951 (Box 3, Folder 3)